Guide to the Time Inc. Corporate Administration Records 1853-1997 MS 3009-RG 5
New-York Historical Society
- Subseries IV.A. Treasurer's Office Records: Treasurer J. Winston Fowlkes Files, 1971-1987, undated; 8 Linear feet (8 boxes)
  - Subsubseries V.__.2. Computer Television, Inc., 1971-1974; 4 Linear feet; (4 boxes)
    - Hilton [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R16)
    - Hilton Payroll: Statistics (Offsite-box 820, Folder 9)
    - Hilton Hotels: Personnel [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R16)
    - Hilton Status (Offsite-box 820, Folder 10)
    - Hotel Movies: Correspondence, Statistics and Worksheets (Offsite-box 820, Folder 11)
    - Jussim Schedules [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R16)
    - Paul Kagan Associates Conference (Offsite-box 820, Folder 12)
    - Paul Klein Employment Option [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R16)
    - Lincoln Center (Offsite-box 820, Folder 13)
    - Loan Guarantees (Offsite-box 820, Folder 14)
    - Loan Guarantees [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R16)
    - Magnavox (Offsite-box 820, Folder 15)
    - Memoranda: 1971-1975 (Offsite-box 820, Folder 16-19)
    - Negotiations: 1971 (Offsite-box 820, Folder 20-21)
    - Negotiations: 1971 [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R16)
    - Office Space (Offsite-box 820, Folder 22)
    - Office Space [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R16)
    - Payments [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R16)
    - Personnel (Offsite-box 820, Folder 23)
    - Projections (Offsite-box 820, Folder 24)
    - Quality Courts (Offsite-box 820, Folder 25)
    - Ramada Inn (Offsite-box 820, Folder 26)
    - Reports (Offsite-box 820, Folder 27)
    - Schroder Capital Corp. [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R16)
    - Staff Memos (Offsite-box 820, Folder 28)
    - Successive Closing (Offsite-box 820, Folder 29)
    - Trans World Communications: Agreements [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R16)
    - Trans World Communications: Assets (Offsite-box 820-821)
    - Trans World Communications: Assets [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R16)
    - Trans World Communications Inc.: Board Meetings (Offsite-box 821, Folder 2)
    - Trans World Communications Inc.: Board Meetings [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R16)
    - Trans World Communications: Hotel Agreements [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R16)
    - Trans World Communications: Legal [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R16)
    - Trans World Communications: Meetings (Offsite-box 821, Folder 3)
    - Trans World Communications: Sale to Rogers Cable (Offsite-box 821, Folder 4)
    - Trans World Communications: Sale to Rogers Cable [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R16)
    - Trans World Communications: General (Offsite-box 821, Folder 5-6)
    - Travelers Television (Offsite-box 821, Folder 7)
    - Twentieth Century Fox (Offsite-box 821, Folder 8)
    - Slater Walker (Offsite-box 821, Folder 9)
    - Yaeger Schedules [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R16)
    - Year End Closing: 1973 (Offsite-box 821, Folder 10)
    - Year End Closing: 1973 [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R16)
    - Miscellaneous (Offsite-box 821, Folder 11)
    - General Information (Offsite-box 821, Folder 12)
  - Subsubseries V.__.3. Investor Relations, 1977-1987, undated; 2 Linear feet; (2 boxes)
    The Investor Relations files cover the period of 1977 to 1987 and focus on J. Winston Fowlkes's work as Director of Investor Relations and heading the committee handling the restructuring of Time Inc.'s agreement with the American Television and Communication Corporation. Combined with Fowlkes's documents, are documents created by Peter Uebelhoer and Thayer Bigelow, members of the restructuring committee.
    Urban "Peter" Uebelhoer joined the corporate finance staff as Assistant Treasurer in October 1981 serving through 1983 under Treasurer J. Winston Fowlkes. From 1984 through 1986, Uebelhoer served as Treasurer and oversaw Cash Management and Fiduciary Investments.
    Thayer Bigelow became Vice President and Treasurer of Time Inc. in 1982 and remained in this position for a year. From 1983 to 1987, he served as Chief Financial Officer.
    Organized into two subsubsubseries: Subsubsubseries V.__.3.A. American Television and Communication Corporation, and Subsubsubseries V.__.3.B. Subject files.
    - Subsubsubseries V.__.3.A. American Television and Communication Corporation, 1977-1987, undated; 1 Linear feet; (1 box)
      The American Television and Communication Corporation (ATC) files focus on the financial relationship between Time Inc. and ATC. The majority of documents deal with the restructuring of Time Inc. and ATC's financial relationship and the creation of an investor relations program. Included among the materials found in this subsubsubseries are memos and correspondence sent to the members of Time Inc.'s financial group, lists of investor relations consultants, financial restructuring proposals, lists of major institutional holders in cable companies, financial reports, clippings, press releases, security exchange committee reports, Q&As from research analysis meetings, common stock prospectuses, meeting schedules and outlines for conference, reports and printouts of presentations analyzing the finances of ATC, meeting itineraries, notes, and annual reports and financial reports of ATC.
      - General (Offsite-box 821, Folder 13-16)
      - General [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R16)
      - Analysts Reports (Offsite-box 821, Folder 17)
      - Annual Report (Offsite-box 821, Folder 18)
      - Class A Common Stock (Offsite-box 821, Folder 19)
      - Debt Offering (Offsite-box 821, Folder 20)
      - Donaldson, Lufkin & Jenrette (Offsite-box 821, Folder 21)
      - The Enrcom (Offsite-box 821, Folder 22)
      - Financing (Mile Hi) (Offsite-box 821, Folder 23)
      - Financing (Mile Hi) [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R16)
      - First Boston (Offsite-box 821, Folder 24)
      - Form S-1: Registration Statement (Offsite-box 821, Folder 25-26)
      - Manhattan Cable: Financial Statement (Offsite-box 821, Folder 27)
      - Merril Lynch (Offsite-box 821, Folder 28)
      - Notes and Debentures (Offsite-box 821, Folder 29)
      - Preliminary Draft: Financial Statements and Notes (Offsite-box 821, Folder 30)
      - Press Releases (Offsite-box 822, Folder 1)
      - Rating Agency Presentation (Offsite-box 822, Folder 2)
      - Restructuring: Background (Offsite-box 822, Folder 3)
      - Restructuring: Press Release (Offsite-box 822, Folder 4)
    - Subsubsubseries V.__.3.B. Subject files, 1978-1987, undated; 1 Linear feet; (1 box)
      The Subject files focus on companies in which Time Inc. invested in or were considering for investment. Materials include memos and correspondence sent to the members of Time Inc.'s financial group, requests for investments, financial reports of possible investments, agreements, and meeting schedules. Additionally, there are handwritten notes, newspaper clippings, press releases, annual reports, stock certificates, invoices, and transcripts of speeches.
      - Anti-Takeover: 1984 (Offsite-box 822, Folder 5-6)
      - Anti-Takeover: 1984 [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R17)
      - Bank Accounts/Relations: Stillman Memo to Board: 10/18/50 (Offsite-box 822, Folder 7)
      - Banks: Miscellaneous (Offsite-box 822, Folder 8)
      - Building Sale (Offsite-box 822, Folder 9)
      - Corporate Finance: Staff Meetings (Offsite-box 822, Folder 10)
      - Correspondence: Fowlkes: 1986-1987 (Offsite-box 822, Folder 11)
      - Correspondence: Fowlkes: 1986-1987 [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R17)
      - Correspondence: Uebelhoer: 1987 (Offsite-box 822, Folder 12-14)
      - Correspondence: Uebelhoer: 1987 [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R17)
      - Debentures (Offsite-box 822, Folder 15)
      - Debt Capacity (Morgan) (Offsite-box 822, Folder 16)
      - Explosive Fabricators (Offsite-box 822, Folder 17-18)
      - Explosive Fabricators [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R17)
      - Explosive Fabricators: Stock Shares (Offsite-box 822, Folder 19)
      - Explosive Fabricators: Stock Shares [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R17)
      - Marty Lipton Takeover Proposal (Offsite-box 822, Folder 20)
      - Marty Lipton Takeover Proposal [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R17)
      - MCTV Revolver (Offsite-box 822, Folder 21)
      - MCTV Revolver [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R17)
      - Private Investment Company of Asia (PICA) (Offsite-box 822, Folder 22)
      - Revolving Credit Agreement: 1986 [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R17)
      - Southern Progress Corporation: Southern Living (Offsite-box 822, Folder 23-24)
      - Speeches (Offsite-box 823, Folder 1)
      - Stock Repurchase Plan (Offsite-box 823, Folder 2)
      - Stock Repurchase Program: 1986 (Offsite-box 823, Folder 3)
      - Strategy (Offsite-box 823, Folder 4-5)
      - Tenth Annual Paine Webber Mitchell Hutchins Conference on the Outlook for the Media Program (Offsite-box 823, Folder 6)
      - Time Inc. (Offsite-box 823, Folder 7)
      - Time Inc. Stock: Series B (Offsite-box 823, Folder 8)
      - Tri-Star Pictures, Inc. (Offsite-box 823, Folder 9)
      - Tri-Star Pictures, Inc. [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R17)
      - Wayfarer Ketch Corp. (Offsite-box 823, Folder 10)
      - Working Woman, Inc. (Offsite-box 823, Folder 11)
- Subseries IV.B. Treasurer's Office Records: Assistant Treasurer Allen Barr Files, 1979-1988; 2.5 Linear feet (3 boxes)
  The Allen Barr files include his files and files transferred to him by others working under him while he was both Assistant Treasurer of Time Inc. and Financial Planning Manager of the Magazine Group. The files look like part of alphabetically subject files (the S section) and chronological files regarding analysts meetings and annual reports. The Shareholders Correspondence is from Barbara Sangerman and contains shareholders' concerns how the Time Inc. offices in South Africa navigated apartheid and Time Inc.'s responses. Some of the 1987 Analysts Meeting files were transferred from Victor Sauerhoff. The Annual Reports records include distribution instructions, drafts and a proof copy, and proposals for changes. The Analysts Meeting records include attendee lists, reports, and presentation speeches and slide printouts.
  - South Africa: Shareholders Correspondence: 1979-1985 (Offsite-box 823, Folder 12-14)
  - Speeches [of others] (Offsite-box 823, Folder 15-18)
  - Stock Surveillance Reports (Offsite-box 823, Folder 19-21)
  - Survey: 1982 Annual Report (Offsite-box 823-824)
  - Analysts Meetings and Visits: 1987 (Offsite-box 824, Folder 2-13)
    Includes one audiocassette.
    1 audiocassette: analog, 1 5/16 ips, stereo; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. Label: "4/3/87 Analysts Meeting."
  - Annual Report: 1987 (Offsite-box 824-825)
  - Analysts Meetings: 1988 (Offsite-box 825, Folder 6-16)